This is our group chat topic of the week.
We ask, does the portrayal and representation of Black people in cinema and TV matter anymore,
or is it all about entertainment?
Of course, imagery matters.
Martin Luther King made sure to always have on a shirt and tie and suit whenever they
were doing protests and knowing they were going to be assaulted because they knew that
the imagery mattered.
I believe that imagery does matter.
I believe as somebody who has been in Hollywood that we do have to gatekeep, and that the
best way that you gatekeep ultimately on the outside is by just not supporting the stuff
that isn't representative in the way that you want it to be.
And on the inside, folks need to be willing to say, no, this is not good.
This is not OK.
You know, and that's the other part.
A lot of Black folks in these rooms, they don't want to say that because they don't want to
either look like the token or they don't want to look like they don't want to look like
a man of seals.
That's really what they be on.
If media wasn't so important, the government would not be so deeply entrenched in it.
And it is very deeply entrenched in ways that so many of us really don't know.
For a lot of Black people, our ability to be heard only came through media because, I
mean, through particularly cinema and television, because when we're represented in the news,
it's always as thugs, you know, or welfare queens, like there was always so much negativity.
So when you saw imagery that was actually counter to that, a lot of times it was in pop culture.
I mean, Boys in the Hood was, there was a message at the end, you know, either they don't
know, don't show or don't care about what's going on in the hood.
We are, we are, we are.